Rikie Patrick

Software Engineer

in rikie-patrick

1sAndZeros

rikiepatrick@gmail.com | +447949 459 097 | www.rpatrick.dev





Summary

I'm a Software Developer with an 11-year background as a Programming Engineer, working on coding and running CNC machines in the aerospace industry. Having progressed quickly throughout the manufacturing engineering space, my interests in technology and coding started to grow which led me to self-study web development prior to my time at Makers. Being able to leverage real world skills across critical thinking and problem solving, I have further developed my technical capacity across HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to advanced technologies such as React, Node.js, and Python. My professional passions lie in working with different teams to ensure a customer-centric approach, as well as product and tool enhancements.



Technical Skills

LanguagesHTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, React, Python, Swift	TestingPlaywright, Jest, Cypress, Pytest
Databases • PostgreSQL, MongoDB	Version Control • Git, Github
	1 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0



Projects

Project	Description	Tech Stack
MyPlace	Web App to track visited and desired locations and share your	React, JavaScript, CSS, Node, Express, Jest, Mapbox, Bcrypt
	travel map with friends	Express, sest, Mapsox, Berypt
Acebook	Group project recreating a social	React, MongoDB, Express,
	media web app	JavaScript, Node, Jest, Cypress
MakersBnB	Group project building an AirBnB	Python, Flask, PostgreSQL,
	clone	Pytest



Work Experience

Software Engineering Student

Makers Academy - July 2023 to October 2023

- Collaborated on diverse group projects, using pair programming techniques to enhance problem-solving efficiency and communication skills, delivering high-quality solutions.
- Participated in emotional intelligence workshops, fostering the ability to recognize and manage emotions both personally and in team dynamics.
- Embraced a test-driven development approach throughout coding challenges, effectively using testing frameworks such as Pytest, Jest, Playwright, and Cypress.



- Engaged in regular code reviews with peers, providing and receiving constructive feedback.
- Demonstrated adaptability by acquiring new programming languages and frameworks and successfully applying them to various projects.
- Acted as a mentor to fellow bootcamp participants, sharing knowledge and expertise.
- Demonstrated proficiency in Agile methodologies and successfully implemented the Model-View-Controller (MVC) architectural pattern in various coding bootcamp projects.

Ipeco Holdings Ltd - World-class aerospace manufacturer of pilot seating and galley equipment where I used advanced programming and machining techniques to produce high-quality components using CNC machine tools.

Programming Engineer (CNC Machining) - September 2014 to Present

- Investigated new software and technologies in order to develop the business.
- Liaised with the Engineering Department to ensure manufacturability of new design solutions as well as assisting in the development of new projects and technologies.
- Designed tooling solutions to support in-house manufacturing processes.
- Reviewed existing manufacturing processes with a view to deliver product cost, time related and/or quality improvements.
- Trained new members of staff on the relevant software and machine tools.
- Identified and implemented cost-effective manufacturing solutions.
- Liaised with various departments to deliver new projects in a timely manner.

Technical Apprentice - November 2012 to September 2016

- Developed core engineering skills such as milling, turning, hand fitting.
- Participated in the activities of 'Continuous Improvement' within the Group
- Undertook various ad-hoc projects as required to support the changing requirements of the business.
- Completed several qualifications and training courses including a HNC and NVQ Level 2 and 3
- Gained good knowledge of an engineering company by working in 12 different departments over a 12-month period.
- Regularly used manual milling machines, lathes and CNCs to produce components.



Education

BTEC Level 4 HNC Diploma in Mechanical Engineering - Distinction

Havering College - September 2014 to August 2016

 Analytical Methods for Engineers, Engineering Science, Project Design, Implementation and Evaluation, Mechanical Principles, Applications of Pneumatics and Hydraulics, Fluid Mechanics, Strength of Materials, Advanced CAD, Business Techniques for Engineers

BTEC Level 3 National Certificate in Mechanical Engineering - Distinction Merit SEEVIC College - September 2007 to August 2009